<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The love of God is to gather the seasons of the earth and their multitudes into peace in opening the Scriptures and the mysteries of the revalations to them and their multitudes that they may come to live in obedience to the Gospel power ; doing the work of God through the son of Peace, which Son of Peace is Christ the Lord.</title>
            <author>Redford, Elizabeth.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1711</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 45 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 5 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2012-10">2012-10 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A58325</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing R660A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R28472</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">10603788</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 10603788</idno>
            <idno type="VID">45364</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A58325)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 45364)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1408:47)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The love of God is to gather the seasons of the earth and their multitudes into peace in opening the Scriptures and the mysteries of the revalations to them and their multitudes that they may come to live in obedience to the Gospel power ; doing the work of God through the son of Peace, which Son of Peace is Christ the Lord.</title>
                  <author>Redford, Elizabeth.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>8 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1711?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Signed at end: Elizabeth Redford.</note>
                  <note>Imprint suggested by NUC pre 1956 imprints. Wing has 1690 as date of publication.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Harvard University Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Society of Friends --  Pastoral letters and charges.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2011-02</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-02</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-07</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-07</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:45364:1"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:45364:1"/>
            <head>THE LOVE of GOD, IS TO Gather the <hi>Seaſons</hi> of the <hi>Earth;</hi> AND Their Multitudes into PEACE.</head>
            <head type="sub">In <hi>Opening</hi> the <hi>Scriptures,</hi> and the <hi>Myſteries</hi> of the <hi>Revelations</hi> to them, and their <hi>Multitudes</hi> that they may come to <hi>Live</hi> in <hi>Obedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ence</hi> to the <hi>Goſpel Power;</hi> doing the <hi>Work</hi> of <hi>God,</hi> through the <hi>Son</hi> of <hi>Peace,</hi> which <hi>Son</hi> of <hi>Peace</hi> is <hi>Chriſt</hi> the <hi>Lord.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>THE Angel of Power, wh<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> I <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ve with my Spirit, (C<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>riſt the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>d.) Dictates in me; t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap> is a neceſſity <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>or <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> ſecond Coming in Revel<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="5 letters">
                  <desc>•••••</desc>
               </gap>, or the W<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>rld will be Loſt, in Re<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ellion, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>here is a neceſſity, for a further Revelation of the G<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ſpel, which is Peace, in the Son of Peace; or the Dragon will yet further, keep up his Reign: <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> a furthe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ſt<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ucti<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>n in wars, and ſlaughters, to the further confuſion of Nations, and their Multitudes which fall, and are in the Diſobe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dience to the Goſpel, which is Peac<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>, and are ſeen in the fall and falſe Worſhip, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>th to God and M<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>n; ſo that the examples of the Chriſtian Faith, which came for Peace, are uſeleſs to the waring World, both to the name Chriſtian, which ought to be Examples, till the Faith is Eſtabliſhed; and by ſuch pra<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>ces, of the name Chriſtians, the Wo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ld is kept in Darkneſs, to that the name Turks, nor the name Heathen, are not ga<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ered home to the Faith of Chriſtian; and Peace of the Son of Peace; <hi>for wh<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>h them, called <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>ſtions, and which makes a Profeſſion if the Faith of of a Chriſtian, muſt give an Account off, (to the Powers above) which pretend to be Leaders and Teachers of the People belo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>,</hi> for Man is not to be <hi>Worſhiped with Mens Lives under the Goſpel, but to love as Brethren, both Rulers and People, in their ſeveral degrees, and Nations to be in unity with th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Son of Peace, bringing their greatneſs, into his ſuffering, for Peace and Love;</hi> and when the Nations are gathered into the Faith, which gives Power, in the Son of Peace, and in the Faith of Jeſus, which came an Example of Peace; they will be peaceable, an<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> the Chriſt in Faith will be Eſtabliſhed: But <hi>John</hi> in the Divine Nature ſaw, <hi>they Which came not to be followers of the Lamb, fell with the Dragon: So this ſheweth, there is but a true Church or a Falſe; of every Nation which is to follow the Lamb, or Worſhip the Dra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gon,</hi> and to be a follower of the Lamb, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>eads to <hi>Wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip him, that made Heaven and Earth, the Sea and the Fountains of Water, and to give Glory to him.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>And as there is one Glory in the Sun, and another Glory of the Moon, and another Glory of the Stars:</hi> So the Glory of the Father, <hi>through the Lamb and his followers, is powerful over the Dragon Spirit, and his followers;</hi> not<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>withſtanding
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:45364:2"/> it may yet be, through great Suffering; (for the Eſtabliſhing the Goſpel univerſally,) <hi>the Lamb and his Followers are Redeemed from the Earth, and are led in Peace and Truth, to Glorifie him, that made Heaven and Earth, the Sea, and the Fountains of of Water; and the Dragon leads his Followers in Errour, and ſlaughter, till their meaſure is full, to their own Deſtruction, and are ſwallowed up in the Earth,</hi> they contend for; and God who made Heaven and Earth, the Sea and the Fountains of Water, is Glorifi'd in their Deſtruction; and the Word of God ſtands for ever to the Faithfull and Obedient, that work the Work of God, In Peace to their Salvation; and the Lambs Spirit cannot touch with the Dragon's Spirit, nor the Dragon's Spirit over-power <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>he Lambs Spirit, becauſe God's Power in the Lamb, and his Followers (Redeemed from the Earth,) gained the Victory over the Dragons Spirit, and the Dragons Power and Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rit; to be in Subjection for ever, to Truth, the Word of God; and when the Dragon is caſt into the Earth, the record is; <hi>he joyned with the Beaſt riſing up out of the Sea, and he perſecuted the Church, called the Wo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man, and in his Wrath, went to make war with the Remnant of the Seed, which keep the Commandments of God, and have the Teſtimony of Jeſus Chriſt, and to be in Chriſt, brings Salvation; Rev.</hi> 12. <hi>c.</hi> 17 <hi>v.</hi> And the Church in Chriſt, <hi>be firſt Born, hath ever been powerfull, with the Father,</hi> is the Witneſſes before the Law, and in the time of the Law, and in the Goſpel bear Teſtimony. <hi>Heb.</hi> 12. <hi>c.</hi> 23.28 <hi>v. c.</hi> 13.14 <hi>v. c.</hi> 11. 10 <hi>v.</hi> And Chriſt was with the Church, in the Wilderneſs, and Sea; leading up the Flock, in Days of Old, and hath appeared in Man, for the uniting the Church, in the Peace of the Goſpel, keeping the Commandments of God, which God and Power, is from everlaſting, to everlaſting, without begining of Days, or end of Time, And to be of the Church, of the firſt Born, is to be <hi>in Chriſt, and to be in Chriſt, is to be a Chriſtian, and to be a Chriſtian, is to ſuffer Perſecution, till the Church of Chriſt is Eſtabliſhed in Peace upon Earth,</hi> that both Rulers and People may Live, in Chriſt peaceable Kingdom, for which Eſtabliſhment, the Power of God in Man, hath deſcended, and is made manifeſt, that Nations ſhould be Redeemed into Peace and Obe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dience, following the Example of the Son of Peace, and the Church in Chriſt, are the Worſhippers in Spirit and Truth, of every Nation, and the D<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ſobe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dient, to the Spirit of Chr<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ſt, to gain the Earth, (which they muſt leave,) they follow the Dragon, and Worſhip him with their Lives and Subſtance: As<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> 
               <hi>John</hi> in the <hi>Revelations,</hi> gives the Account. <hi>Rev.</hi> 13. c. 4 <hi>v.</hi> But them which fear God, and work Righteouſneſs, are excepted of every Nation, u<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ited to him in the Peace of the Son of Peace; as ſaith <hi>Pe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>er,</hi> of a Truth, I perceive, that God is no Reſpecter of Perſons, but in every Nation, he that feareth God, and worketh Righte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ouſneſs, is accepted with him. <hi>Acts.</hi> 10. <hi>c</hi> 34.35 <hi>v.</hi> And where the fear of God is in Truth, ſuch their labour and travel is to Obey the S<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>n of Peace, and where Obedience is to God, and the Lambs Peace, the Dragons nature is kept down, and the Power of God will caſt his power down, through Nations, which follow the Example, and Obedience of the Son, which came to Manifeſt the way of Peace and Truth, and ſuch labour in the Obedience, and Heavenly War, as <hi>Michael</hi> and his Angels did, againſt the Dragon and his Angels, and it was truth, which overcame the Dragon in Heaven, and not Swords; and it is Truth, in the Chriſtian Faith, which muſt overcome the Dra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gon upon Earth, and not Swords. And the Power of G<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>d was with his Truth, and caſt the Old Serpent called the Devil, and Satan with his Angels, from Hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven. And it is the Power of God which muſt caſt the Dragon, and Old Serpent out of Mens earth here and not Swords. And as Nations keep to Truth, ſo to ſtand or fall to their own Maſter, notwithſtanding the Dragon had a Power with his Angels, yet the Po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wer of God which is with his Truth, is above the Po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wers of Darkneſs, and his Angels, and they were caſt into the Earth, <hi>and the Chriſtians are to ſit in the Heavenly place, with Chriſt their Holy Head, which Power Deſcended and appeared in Jeſus, to ſave Men's Lives, and not to deſtroy Men's Lives, and that all ſhould be gathered to God both Jew and Gentile, and that all ſhou'd come into the Spirit and Obedience of the Son of Peace</hi> which bid Peter, <hi>put up thy Sword again into his Place, for all they that take the Sword ſhall Periſh with <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>he Sword.</hi> Mat. 26 c. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> v <hi>And</hi> Gen. 9 c. 6, <hi>v. and</hi> Rev. 13 <hi>c.</hi> 10. <hi>v. And the Miniſtration</hi> of the Goſpel, ſheweth Peace, to them in Chriſt, and that ſuch as lo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> their Chri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtian liberty of Peace, in the Glorious Liberty of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>e Son of God, they enter Satans Bondage and Wars, and are not Redeemed from the Earth, they contend for, and fall with their contending, to the deſtroying their Mul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>titudes, and Liberties of Peace, through the Son of Peace, ſent an Example of Peace; and under the diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>penſation of the Goſpel, in the Goſpel, in the Chriſtian Faith, there is no Examples of King-makers, or for Chriſtians in the Faith, to pull down Kings, (for) when Jeſus perceived they would come and take him by force, to make him a King, he departed again, into a Moun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain alone. <hi>John.</hi> 6. <hi>c.</hi> 15 <hi>v.</hi> And he ſaith to <hi>Pilate, my Kingdom is not of this World, if my Kingdom were of this World, then w<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>uld my Servants Fight, that I ſhould not be delivered to the</hi> Jews; <hi>but now is my Kingdom not from hence.</hi> John 18. <hi>c.</hi> 36. <hi>v But his</hi> King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom was, to bear Witneſs to the Truth, for which cauſe Jeſus declares, that he was Born to this end, and cauſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> to bear Witneſs to the Truth, which Truth <hi>Pilate</hi> knew not, and ſaith <hi>what is Truth?</hi> but Truth reached ſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> fa<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> to <hi>Pilate,</hi> that he ſaid to the <hi>Jews, I find no fault a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> all in him:</hi> The Examples of the Goſpel in Chriſt kep<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> right on their way, and did not turn, to the righ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> hand, of to the left for grandure, but goodneſs, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> they went through many Tribulations and Suffering<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> and with the Fathers and Prophets in the Faith, d<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>clared. <hi>Here have we no continuing City, but we ſe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <pb n="3" facs="tcp:45364:2"/> one to come;</hi> Heb. 13 c.. 14 v. 11 c. 10 v. <hi>a City, which hath Foundation, whoſe Builder, and maker is God.</hi> And the Chriſtians now are to keep right on their way, to ſeek this City, which hath Foundation in the Truth, till they have made their Peace with God, in the Spirit of the Son, that a ſeed in the uni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſal Love, may be planted in the Heavenly Can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>naan, and Spiritual Jeruſalem; and ſo to go on, to the perfecting their Obedience, in the Faith of a Chri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtian, and to ſhew forth their Obedience, whilſt hear, for the gathering of more into the Peace of the Son of Peace, notwithſt nding it may be through great Suf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferings, and Tribulations for the ſake of Peace and Truth, and that Chriſts Kingdom of Peace, may be Eſtabliſhed in every Nation, that the other Sheep, which are not come, to be of his Spiritual Fold, may be gathered to the Kingdom of Peace, and to Wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip God in Spirit and Truth, for ſuch the Father ſeeks to Worſhip him, and theſe Worſhipers in the Power of Truth; the one Church in Chriſt is the way to the Father, and the Churches of every Nation eſtabliſhed by the Law, of Men, will come to Nothing. It is the Church eſtabliſhed by Grace, that will ſtand, of every Nation; and the Dragons Power brought down by the Power of Truth. The Dragon and Serpent, which is Lucifer, was once called the Son of the Morning, and he was in Heaven as an Ang<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>l of Light, yet could not ſtand in a Preſumtious Spirit, but the Truth caſt him and his Angels down, notwithſtanding he was ſo Powerful; amongſt the Stars, <hi>Iſa.</hi> 14 <hi>c.</hi> 12 <hi>v. His all drew the Third part of the Stars of Heaven and did caſt them to the Earth, in his fall,</hi> and Truth the one Church, will y<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>t diſappoint him, and his Angels, and Stars upon Earth; let the Profection be never ſo High, and the Name of Church never ſo great, ye<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> God will ſtand by his Truth, and will bring down every falſe Worſhipper, notwithſtand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, Truth may and ye muſt ſuffer, till the peacea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble Kingdom of Chriſt is Eſtabliſhed, and ſuch as keep to the Spirit of Truth, will gain the Victory with the Lamb, and they which abuſe in <hi>Chriſt, the Light and Lif<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>, the Truth and the way,</hi> are in the one Church, and they in the Light, keep out of the Dragons <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>the, as they keep to Chriſt, the one Church in the Spirit of Truth, which Truth is Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vealed in the Lamb, and his Followers, and unites, in the o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> holy Building, with <hi>the Bride, the Lambs Wife,</hi> and with the Tribes, of the Children of <hi>Iſrael,</hi> and the Apoſtles of the Lamb; ſo that the True Church is ſignified by <hi>the Lamb, and his followers in Peace,</hi> from the falſe Worſhippers, <hi>the Dragon, and his followers, in Wars joined to Miſtery</hi> Babylon, which is recorded, <hi>ſitteth upon many waters, upon a Scarlet Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lour'd Beaſt,</hi> and <hi>Miſtery Babylon, Is full of Names of Blaſphemy, and the Beaſt ſhe ſitteth upon, having ſeven Heads, and ten Hornes,</hi> which Hornes, the Angel interprets to <hi>John</hi> be <hi>Kings.</hi> Rev. 17 <hi>c.</hi> 12 <hi>v. And they Worſhipped the Dragon, which gave Power to the Beaſt, (with ſeven Heads, and ten Hornes,) ſaying, who is like unto the Beaſt, who is able to make War with him.</hi> Rev. 13 c. 4. <hi>v.</hi> 10. <hi>c.</hi> 13 v. <hi>&amp; there was given to the Beaſt, a mouth ſpaeking great things and Blaſphemies.</hi> And as the Waters ſignifies, Peoples, and Multitudes, and Nations, and Tongues; 17 <hi>c.</hi> 15 <hi>v.</hi> So <hi>Babylon</hi> ſignifies, the falſe Church, guided by the falſe Spirit; of every People, and Multitudes, and Nations, and Tongues, and to be brought down, and ſit in the Duſt, and to have no Throne, as the Prophet <hi>Iſaiah</hi> ſaw, and ſit ſilent, for as ſaith the Prophet, ſpeaking of the falſe Church, <hi>thou ſhalt no more be called, the Lady of King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>doms,</hi> 47 c. 1. 5 v. Jer. 50 c. 1 v. 51. <hi>c</hi> 7 v. Rev. 18 <hi>c.</hi> 2 <hi>v.</hi> 14 <hi>c.</hi> 8 <hi>v.</hi> And to be guided by the falſe Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rit in Worſhip, is called Whoredoms, as the Old and and New Teſtaments, and the Revelations of the An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gel of Jeſus Chriſt, to <hi>John</hi> ſignifies, and <hi>John</hi> when in the Spirit, ſaw <hi>Miſtery of</hi> Babylon <hi>the great, her Name</hi> written (for Deſtruction) <hi>the Mother, of Har<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lots, and abominations of the Earth,</hi> and I ſaw the Woman <hi>Drunker,</hi> (ſaith John,) <hi>with the Blood of Saints, and with the Blood of the Martyrs, of Jeſus.</hi> So it is plain, Babylon is a Mixture of Confuſion (in Worſhip) a people led by the falſe Spirit of every Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, apart, which come not to the Obedience and Peace in the Goſpel, which the Father ſent the Son of Peace with, that the Dragon and his Power, and Worſhippers might be brought down, to have no fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Place in the Heavenly Part, nor <hi>to draw the Stars of Heaven to the Earth with his Tail,</hi> for the Dragon aſſuming a Power, in Heaven, which did not belong to him, is caſt d<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>wn and Men which the Dragon works in, and they in a High Profeſſion, in Religion, ſuch aſſume a Power which does not be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>long to the Chriſtian Faith, to Perſecute or to j<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>in in War, to kill or deſtroy, and as the Dragon gained a Power over the Angels, and the Stars of Heaven, as appearing as an Angel of Light; ſo Men in whom the Drag n works, and they appear in a High Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſſion, in Religion, and perform ſome Religious Dutys, it is ſuch which draw Angelical Spirits to them which are off of their Watch, and ſuch Stars with their tail, (a Power which they have begotten in the Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple through their great appearance and Bright<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>eſs of appearance) to follow them to their own Deſtruction, at the Dragon did the Angels and Stars of Heaven; and did caſt them to the Earth. So man in a dege<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nerated State; is a Tail to the Dragon, to draw dege<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nerated Spirits to them, men which have been Viſited with an Angelical Spirit, and have Shined as Stars, but go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing from their firſt <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ove and Viſitation, lead the People back again to their great loſs, and ſuch can join with the Dragon, and War, and become as Lions and Dragons, to the People of God; as Man in a degenerated State, is called a Lion and Dragon, as <hi>Pharaoh</hi> and <hi>Nebu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chadnezzar</hi>
               <pb n="4" facs="tcp:45364:3"/> King of <hi>Babylon,</hi> and the King of <hi>Aſſyria</hi> is recorded <hi>Jer.</hi> 50. <hi>c</hi> 17 <hi>v.</hi> 51 <hi>c.</hi> 37. <hi>v</hi> For in the 70 Years Captivity of <hi>Iſrael,</hi> and <hi>Judah</hi> in <hi>Babylon,</hi> they were cruel to <hi>Iſrael</hi> and <hi>Judah;</hi> and the People of God, owning the True God; were Obedient to the Word, which the Prophet had ſpoken, and Worſhipped the True God, which neither the King of <hi>Aſſyria,</hi> nor <hi>Nebuchadnezzar</hi> did they were Worſhippers of Gods, and formed Gods to themſelves, and <hi>Nebuchadnezzar</hi> was deſtroyed in the Houſe of his God, by his Sons, which were Idolaters, as himſelf was, and <hi>Nebuchad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nezzar,</hi> King of <hi>Babylon,</hi> is called the <hi>Hammer of the whole Earth;</hi> (but not a Hammer, in the Work of Salvation, either for himſelf, or Multitudes,) as exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuting the judgments of the Lord, and after to be cut aſunder, and broken, and <hi>Babylon</hi> to become a Deſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lation, among the Nations, that was once ſo great- <hi>Jer.</hi> 50 c. 23.31.15 v. <hi>Shout againſt her, round a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bout, ſhe hath given her hand, her Foundations are fall<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>en, her Walls are thrown down, for it is the Vengeance upon her, as ſhe hath done, do unto her.</hi> So <hi>Babylon</hi> was to be Deſtroyed, whoſe King is called <hi>the Hammer of the whole Earth;</hi> when he had done his office upon the proud, and in executing the Lord's Wrath, upon the Rebellious, to which he was ſent, then others was to be raiſed up againſt him, a mighty Nation, and <hi>Ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bylon</hi> lamented: <hi>O thou that dwelleth upon many waters, aboundant in Treaſures, thine end is come, and the mea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſure of thy Covetouſneſs.</hi> Jer. 51 c. 13 <hi>v.</hi> So one Idolater, was raiſed to deſtroy another, in their Pride, when their meaſure of Iniquity was full; as the Prophet <hi>Iſaiah</hi> ſaw, 14 c. 5.6 <hi>v.</hi> and the Prophet <hi>Ezekiel</hi> gives the account of God's Judgments upon the Prince of <hi>Tyrus,</hi> that had imployed the Wiſdom given him, to gain Riche<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>, as 27 c. ſheweth, and 28 c. <hi>Tyrus</hi> is ſaid to be Wiſer then <hi>Daniel,</hi> there is no ſecret, that they can hide from thee, 3.4. v. <hi>With thy Wiſdom, and with thine <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nderſtanding, thou haſt gotten thee Riches, Gold and Silver into thy Trea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſures, by thy great Wiſdom, and by thy Trafficks, thy Heart is lifted up, becauſe of thy Riches.</hi> 12 v. <hi>take up a lamentation upon the King of</hi> Tyrus, <hi>and ſay unto him, thus ſaith the Lord God; thou ſealed up the ſum full of Wiſdom, and perfect in Beauty,</hi> 13 v. <hi>Thou haſt been in</hi> Eden, <hi>the Garden of God, every precious Stone, was thy Covering,</hi> 14 v. <hi>thou art the Annointed Chureb that covereth. I have ſet th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>eſe, thou waſt upon the Holy Mountain of God, thou haſt walked up and down, in the midſt of the Stones of Fire; thou waſt perfect in thy ways, from the Day that thou waſt Creat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ll Iniquity was found in thee, and</hi> 16 v. <hi>by the Multitude of thy Merchandiz<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>, they fi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>ed the midſt of thee, with Violence, and thou haſt ſinned; therefore, I will caſt thee as profane, out of the Mountain of God, and I will deſtroy thee: O Covering Cherub, from the midſt of the Stones of fire, thine Heart was lifted up, becauſe of thy Beauty, thou haſt corrupted thy Wiſdom, by reaſon of thy brightneſs; I will caſt thee to the ground, I will lay thee before Kings, that they may behold thee, thou haſt defiled thy ſanctuaries, by the Multitudes of thine Iniquities, by the Iniquity of thy Traffick; therefore will I bring forth a fire from the midſt of thee; and I will bring thee to aſhes, upon the Earth, in the ſight of all them, that behold thee, thou ſhalt be a Terror, and never ſhalt thou be any more.</hi> So it is plain the Wiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom, and greatneſs, which God had given this Prince, he turned it into Covetouſneſs and Pride, and loſt the Scepter of his Power, and caſt out as pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fane, of the Mountain of God, as not making a right uſe, of the Wiſdom and Beauty, God had given him, for himſelf, and Multitude, and this is agreea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble to the Parable of the unjuſt Steward; the Child<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ren of this World, are in their Generation, Wiſer then the Children of Light. <hi>Luke</hi> 16 c, 8 <hi>v.</hi> That is to gain Riches and greatneſs in this World, and notwithſtanding, it is ſaid to the King of <hi>Tyrus, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hold thou art Wiſer then</hi> Daniel, <hi>and that no Secret, that they can hide from thee,</hi> yet <hi>Daniel</hi>'s Obedience, out did <hi>Tyrus</hi>'s Wiſdom, and the Angel of Power was great with <hi>Daniel,</hi> and the Angel tells <hi>Daniel,</hi> he <hi>is greatly beloved of God,</hi> which is the beſt Riches, if there ſhould be no Portion in the Earth, but great and mighty Men were raiſed, and not being Obedient to the Laws of God, keeping the Commandments, and the Day of his Reſt, for their Diſobedience they were Raiſed, under the Law to deſtroy one another; becauſe of their Pride and falſe Worſhip, as the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phet ſheweth, <hi>Eze.</hi> 30 <hi>C.</hi> 6 <hi>v.</hi> and <hi>c.</hi> 31 <hi>v. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> 32. and 12 18 <hi>v.</hi> and 35 <hi>c.</hi> 2.10 <hi>v.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>But when the Spring of the Goſpel appeared, the Examples of the Chriſtian Faith, United to the Spirit of God, and they left all to f<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>llow the Lord, and they followed a peace<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ble Saviour, and a healing Phyſician, a feeder of multitudes, who again in the Spirit of Prophecy (which is the Teſtimony of Jeſus, he diſcovered the works of darkneſs, and in the fear of the Lord, he <hi>declared the Word of the Lord, and did the work of the Lord and was Obedient to the Death of the Croſs,</hi> and when Jeſus aſcended into Heaven, his time upon Earth being ſhort, the Angel of Jeſus Chriſt, is ſent to declare the <hi>Judgements of God againſt Sin, and falſe Worſhip</hi> Rev, 9. C. 20.21 v. And that the works of the Dragon, may be brought down, and made manifeſt, that the Lamb of Peace, may gain the Victory over the Earth, in the Spirit of Peace, and Truth take place, over the Dragons Spirit of De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtruction and War, and before the Spring of the Goſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pel, the whole World was in War, but at the Birth of Jeſus, the Angel of the Lord and a Multitude of the Heavenly Hoſt, praiſing God, Proclaiming Peace, ſay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, <hi>Glory to God in the, Higheſt, and on Earth Peace good will towards Men.</hi> Luke 2 <hi>C.</hi> 13 14 v. and Je<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſus was raiſed an Example of the Chriſtian Faith, and the Lord ſent forth a Great manifeſtation, of Peace
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:45364:3"/> through him, that it ſhould be obeyed, and yet the whole World is in War, after ſo great a manifeſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of Peace; and 1711 Year ſince, and a Light is now again ſent forth to the <hi>Caeſars</hi> of the Earth, and the <hi>Revelations</hi> Opened, as they never before this Day were to any, and that the <hi>C<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ſars</hi> may come to ſee the Chriſtian fa<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>h, and that <hi>C<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ſars</hi> Sword, ſhould Ceaſe; and according to the Example of the Chriſtian Faith, to ſuffer in outward things, for the Peace and Salvation, that is in the Goſpel, which Examples of Faithfulneſs, was for the <hi>Caeſars</hi> of the Earth, that they might be Examples, to their multitudes, that the Peace of the Goſpel, might live in the <hi>Cae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſars</hi> of the Earth, and <hi>Caeſars</hi> Sword to Ceaſe, that Salvation upon Ob<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>dience might come to <hi>Caeſar,</hi> and their multitudes, in the place of the Goſpel, and that the <hi>Caeſars</hi> of the Earth ſhould be Ex<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>mples to their multitudes, as Cords to draw to Peace and Love, as Jeſus w<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>s an Example to his Diciples, and drew the multitude after him, and with Compaſſion feed them, with a great Miracle the Loves and fiſhes, as ſhewing the Power of God which is in the Faith to the Faithful, and <hi>they which believed were feed, and healed:</hi> and the Record is, there was a Temptation put upon that prepared Body: <hi>whether it ma<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> lawful to pay Tribute to</hi> Caeſar <hi>or not,</hi> now it muſt be con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſidered, who it was asked him, Tempting him the meſſage of our Lord, being Peace to the World, they were under the Law, and in the Deſtructive Nature, they Crucified him, and although they had a call to the Chriſtian Faith, yet they were not come to be Chriſtians in the Faith, and obedience of the Goſpel, ſo that <hi>C<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ſar</hi> and his Deſtructive Sword, and they were alike, and the <hi>Caeſars</hi> not come from under the Law, but when the <hi>Caeſars</hi> of the Earth comes to be Chriſtians, laying down the Deſtructive Sword, in the peace of the Goſpel, then the Image of Chriſt will appear in them, and the Tribute demanded by them, and paid by the Multitude to do good, and the Deſtructive Sword to ceaſe, for the Appearance of our Lord, is for Peace and Truth, and to ſave Mens Lives, and not to deſtroy them, paying a Tribute as a Traveller through Countries, as in many places it is ſo, to pay ſomething for going over a Bridge, or through a Gate, after ſuch an Hour, or for the M<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nuring of Countreys, ſo that his paying ſuch a Tribute then, and in the time of Peace, is no example of upholding <hi>Caeſars</hi> Sword now, for it was a time of Peace, when Jeſus Miniſtred the word of God, ſo that paying ſuch a Tribute then or now, is no Exam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple to the Chriſtians in the Faith, and peace of the Goſpel, to uphold <hi>Caeſars</hi> Sword now, becauſe the Life of that prepared Body, was laid down, that <hi>Caeſar</hi> ſhould come to be a Chriſtian, and the People gathered into peace, and they which are <hi>Caeſar</hi>'s Friends muſt ſuffer, for the word of their Teſtimonies, till <hi>Caeſar</hi> ſees the Chriſtian Faith, and peace and power of the Goſpel, and in Spirit and Truth come to Chriſt, to Reign with him, by Sufferings, firſt for the Peace, which is in the Goſpel, which leads to the Kingdom of Chriſt in Peace, and as to Tribute to <hi>Caeſar,</hi> true Tribute is to be paid to <hi>Caeſar</hi> in Obedience, and for the uniting of the Chriſtian Faith, and Tranqu<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>lity of their People and Nations, that hath not a ſting, and a point of a Sword at the End, ſuch a Tribute was not paid by the Chriſtians, under the Goſpel, but as a paſſenger in the Work of God, I ſay, that Tribute (o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Cuſtom) Jeſus paid for himſelf, and <hi>Peter</hi> as an Example of the Chriſtian Faith, in Neceſſary things, and Peace according to the Goſpel, which is <hi>Peace and Good Will towards Men,</hi> according to the Voice of the Angel of the Lord, <hi>Lu.</hi> 2. <hi>and</hi> 9 <hi>v. and</hi> 13 <hi>and</hi> 14 <hi>v.</hi> and the Heavenly Hoſt, with the Angel, at the Birth of Jeſus, which Voice is to <hi>Caeſar,</hi> as to their multi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tudes, for till the Proclamation reaches into <hi>Caeſar</hi>'s Heart, the multitude is not ſafe, nor the diſciplined Chriſtians as to the outward Life, if they follow the Example of Jeſus, and his Diſciples, yet muſt be O<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bedient to the great Lord of the whole Earth, for the ſake of the other Sheep: not yet gathered into the peace of the Goſpel and Example of Jeſus, who as the prophet gives the Account, and foreſaw, he had done no Violence, <hi>neither was any Deceit in his Mouth, yet was the ſtroke laid upon him,</hi> Iſaiah 53. <hi>and</hi> 9 v. and let it be conſidered by the <hi>Caeſars</hi> of the whole Earth now, what <hi>Pharoah Nebuchadnezzar,</hi> and <hi>Tyrus,</hi> and <hi>Syrus,</hi> and Mount <hi>Sir,</hi> and <hi>Gog</hi> and <hi>Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gog,</hi> were made great and Wiſe, for it was to wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip the True and Living God, and to do no Iniquity, and to keep the Commands of God, but they forſook the Lord and his Commandments, (which to keep brings forth Peace) and Iniquity and Pride was found in them, and this proved their own Deſtruction one after another, when their meaſure was full, and not<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>withſtanding <hi>Nebuchadnezzar</hi> is called <hi>a King of Kings and the hammer of the whole Earth, and the Servant of God,</hi> as executing the Judgments of the Lord, in bringing down mighty Nations, Idolatrous Kings, I ſay which mighty Nations, when their meaſure of Ini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quity was full, after <hi>Iſraels</hi> 70 Years Captivity, was raiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed up againſt him, to bring him down for his Evils, as he had brought down others, in falſe Worſhip, ſo his being the <hi>hammer of the whole Earth, and called a King of Kings, and a Servant of God,</hi> I ſay his Service was to deſtroy, and not in the Work of Sal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vation, neither for himſelf nor his Multitude, and Man in the deſtroying Nature is called a <hi>Dragon,</hi> which muſt be brought down, before they can come to Peace, <hi>Ez.</hi> 29.3 <hi>v. Pſ.</hi> 74 13.14. <hi>v. Iſ.</hi> 27.1 <hi>v.</hi> 51 <hi>c.</hi> 9. <hi>v.</hi> and when the Angel begins his Revelations to the Seven Churches in <hi>Aſia,</hi> he ſhewed every one of the Churches, wherein they were Juſtified, and wherein they acted againſt the Truth, and the Angel of Revelation ſheweth the Angel of the Church in <hi>Pergamos,</hi> where Satans Seat amongſt them is, ſeated
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:45364:4"/> they were ſuch as had held faſt the Name of God, <hi>when the Faithful Martyr was ſlain amongſt you,</hi> ſaith the Ang<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>l in the Word of the Lord, even in thoſe days, wherein Antipas was <hi>my faithful Martyr, who was Slain among you,</hi> where Satan dwelleth, ſo that not<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>withſtanding their high Profeſſion, they held faſt the Name of God, yet Satans Seat, was amongſt them, <hi>and the Faithful Martyr Slain, where Saten dwelleth,</hi> and yet the whole Church was not charged with this, but ſome amongſt you, <hi>where Satan dwelleth,</hi> and Satan Works moſt in them Powers, which are dege<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nerated from the Truth, and are in the Power, and Seat to Work with him, in his Limited Power, for Satan had no Power nor Seat with the Lamb, and his followers, nor with the great multitude, <hi>which no Man could Number, of all Nations, and Kindreds, and People, and Tongues, which had the Voice, of Sal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vation,; and came out of great Tribulations,</hi> Chap. 7 v. 9 14. And the Angel of Revelation Charges the Angel of the Church of <hi>Pergamos,</hi> with a few things (more) <hi>becauſe thou haſt there them that hold the Doct<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rine of</hi> Balaam, <hi>who taught</hi> Balack <hi>to caſt a ſtumbling Block, before the Children of</hi> Iſrael, <hi>in falſe Worſhip, to eat things Sacrificed, to Idols, and to Commit Fornica<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion.</hi> Num. 25 <hi>c.</hi> and Rev. 2 <hi>c.</hi> 13.14 v. And after this the Revelation gives the account, that Sa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tan is <hi>caſt Down from Heaven, with his Angels and Stars.</hi> c. 12. v. 3.4.9. Yet the falſe Spirit, which he had begotten, worſhiped him upon Earth, as <hi>c.</hi> 13 4. v, ſheweth, and as the Lords care is over his Church, <hi>c.</hi> 14 <hi>v.</hi> 6. So the Angel having the everlaſtnig Goſpel to Preach, to them that dwell on the Earth, <hi>and to every Nation, and Kindred, and Tongue, and People,</hi> (hath a warning) ſaying with a loud voice, <hi>fear God and give Glory to Him, for the hour of his Judgments is come, and Worſhip him that made Heaven and Earth, and the Sea, and the Foun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tains of Water, and there followed another Angel, ſay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing,</hi> Babylon <hi>is fallen, is fallen that great City,</hi> (and ſhewing the cauſe for why ſhe fell) <hi>becauſe ſhe made all Nations Drink of the Wine <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>f the Wrath of her For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nication,</hi> v. 9. (and the Lords care is yet great over his Church, in ſending his Warning Angels, <hi>the Third Angel followed them, ſaying with a loud Voice, if any Man Worſhip the beaſt and his Image and Receive his mark, in his forehead, or in his hand, the ſame ſhall drink of the Wine of the Wrath of God, which is poured out, without Mixture, into the Cup, of his Indig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nation, and he ſhall be Tormented, with fire and Brim<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtone, in the preſence of the Holy Angels, and in the Preſence of the Lamb.</hi> (And as it is ſaid Holy Angel<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>, theſe ſheweth, the Holy Angels, from degenerat<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>d Spirits, and fallen Angels, which once appeared in an Angelical State in Heaven; but fell with the Dragon) and are become Angels of Wrath. So in the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>generation, and true Worſhip of God; there muſt be no mixture, to Worſhip the beaſt nor his Image, nor receive their Markes, nor is there any true Judgement where Satans Seat is; but to be reproved, and as <hi>Antipas</hi> was Slain, where Satan dwelleth, ſo <hi>John</hi> gives the account, the accuſer of our Brethern, is caſt down, which accuſed them, before our God, Day and Night, and here his Power is limited, to have no more place in Heaven. 12 <hi>c.</hi> 8.11 v, (the Brethren) <hi>they overcame him by the Blood of the Lamb, and by the word of their Teſtimony, and they loved not their Lives, unto the Death,</hi> but in faithfullneſs, the Life which is in God, is preſerved for ever, and yet the Angels are ſent forth to call to the People of God, to come out of <hi>Babylon,</hi> and not to fall, with her. 18 <hi>c.</hi> The Angel having great Power, and the Earth, was lighted with his Glory, and he cried mightily, with a ſtrong Voice, (ſaying,) <hi>Babylon the great, is falle<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>, is falle<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>, and is become the Habitation of Devils;</hi> (and ſhewing the Falſe Church, and Spirit of every Nation, and Church apart,) and the hold of every foul Spirit, and a cage of every unclean and hatefull Bird, and 3 v. <hi>For all Nations have drank, of the Wine of the Wrath of her Fornications, and the Kings of the Earth have com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted Fornication with her, and the Merchants of the Earth are Waxed Rich, through the abundance of her Delicacies;</hi> and this <hi>Babylon</hi> is yet to be Deſtroyed, a part of every Nation and Church, and People joined together, from Generation to Generation, till the Goſpel take place, and the Powers of the Earth follow the Example of Jeſus, and ſeek the Peace of the Goſpel, by Living in Obedience to it, and to Preach the Goſpel from Nation to Nation, by the practiſeing part, for the <hi>Babylon,</hi> of every Genera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, it's Diſobedience and Whoredoms, muſt be brought down, and rewarded in Judgment, in every diſpenſation, and People; and the Kings of the Earth, who have committed Fornication, and lived deliciouſly with her, ſhall bewail her, and lament for her, when they ſhall ſee the ſmoke of her Burnings. <hi>Eze.</hi> 27 c. 27.35 v. <hi>Rev.</hi> 18 c. 9.24 v. <hi>In her was found, the Blood of the Prophets and of Saints, and if all that were Slain upon the Earth</hi> 35 v. And the Riches of them which belonged to, and joined with <hi>Babylon</hi> is Named, and ſhe fell with her Riches, Gold and Sil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver and precious Stones and Pe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>rls, and fine Linen, and Purple and Silk, and Scarlet, and all Thin Wood, and all manner of Veſſels of Ivory, and all manner of Veſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſels, of moſt precious Wood, and of Braſs and Iron, and Marble, and Cinnamon, and Odours, and Wine and Oil, and fine Flour and Wheat, and Beaſts and Sheep, and Horſes, and Chariots, and Slaves and Souls of Men; (and let it be conſidered, the Slaug<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter of Men in the <hi>Babylon,</hi> of this Generation of the World, how great it is:) 14 <hi>v.</hi> The Fruit that thy Soul luſted after, are departed from thee, and all things which were dainty and good, are departed from thee, and thou ſhalt find them no more at all<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> and 19 <hi>c.</hi> And after theſe things, (ſaith <hi>John.</hi>) I heard a great Voice of much People, in Heaven ſaying:
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:45364:4"/> 
               <hi>Alleluja, Salvation and Glory, and Honour, and Pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er, unto the Lord our God; for true and Righteous are his Judgments, for he hath Judged the great whore, which did currupt the Earth, with her fornication, and hath avenged the Blood of his Servants, as her hand, and the Elders Worſhipped God, that ſate upon the Throne, ſaying Amen, Alleluja, and a great Voice came out of the Throne, ſaying, Praiſe our God, all ye his Servants, and ye thac fear him, both ſmall and great.</hi> And when <hi>Baby<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lon,</hi> the falſe Spirit, and Church of every Nation join<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed together, <hi>John</hi> ſaw and the Angel gives the account, (the Angel having great power, and the Earth was Lighted with his Glory) <hi>Babylon</hi> was brought down, for all Nations have drunk of the Wine of the Wrath of her Fornication, and partaking of her Sins, they were to partake of her Plagues, and the Falſe Church is repreſented, under the Name of <hi>Babylon,</hi> and the Woman, and great City which Reigneth over the Kings of the Earth, 17 <hi>c</hi> 18 <hi>v.</hi> 9 <hi>c.</hi> 20 <hi>v.</hi> Thoſe under the Torments, were ſuch as Worſhipped Devils. 13 <hi>c.</hi> 4 <hi>v. John</hi> giving an ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>count of them which Worſhipped the Dragon, and beaſt; 8 <hi>v.</hi> all that dwell upon the Earth, ſhall Worſhip him, whoſe names are not Written in the Book of Life, of the Lamb Slain, from the Foun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dation of the World; and <hi>John</hi> calls the Falſe Church, with its bottomleſs Evils, for there is no place to ſet their Foot upon, when the Lord enters into Judg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, for great Abominations commited; <hi>John</hi> calls the Falſe Church, (as aforementioned,) the Beaſt was taken, and with him, the Falſe Prophet, that wrought Miracles before him, with which he deceiv<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed them, that had received the Mark of the Beaſt, and them that Worſhipped his Image, <hi>and</hi> John <hi>ſaw</hi> the Kings of the Earth, and their Armies gather together, to made War againſt him, that ſate upon the Houſe, (who was that) his Name is called, Faithful and True, which will bring down Babylons falſe Powers, of every Nation Joyned together, out of the L<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>mb of Peace. <hi>c.</hi> 19. and Univerſal Love, and the Angel ſtanding in the Sun, he cried with a <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>oud Voice, ſaying to all the fowls that flie in the midſt of Heaven; come and ga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther your ſelves together, <hi>c.</hi> 19 <hi>v.</hi> 18. (And the Slaughter was great) that ye may eat the fleſh of Kings and the Fleſh of Captains, and the Fleſh of Mighty Men, and the Fleſh of Horſes, and them that ſet on them, and the Fleſh of all Men, both free and bound both ſmall and great: So here is a part which were as dung, upon the Earth, and for the fowls to feed on (as in Slughters where multitudes fall, they do) and as there is a Worm, which never dies. The beaſt was taken, and with him the falſe Prophet, (as aforemention<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ed) that wrought Miracles before him, with which he Deceived them, that had received the mark of the beaſt, and them that Worſhipped his Image, theſe both were caſt alive, into a Lake of Fire, burning with Brimſtone; and the remnant were ſlain, with the Sword of him, that ſate upon the Horſe, which Sword Proceeded out of his Mouth, and all the fowls were filled with their fleſh, ſo hear John ſaw, that Judgement was ſeveraly given, againſt the beaſt, and fal e Prophet; and the Kings and Captains, and Mighty Men, and all Men, both Free and B und, both Small and great; which Joyned with Babylon, and under the Law, the Kings of Babylon were Idolaters, ſuch as knew not God, and were raiſed to bring down others, in the Idolatries, going from the Law of Truth, in which themſelves was found, and with which the Prophets one after another, charges them Kings of Babylon with, which is no rule for Chriſtians, under the Goſpel to war one Nation with ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, nor to join to ſuch Powers as the Heathen do, to Worſhip the Dragon, and receive his mark in war, and the Heathen is that Old Serpent, called the Devil, which Confuſes the World, to make partyes, as in Heaven he did. The Angels and Stars which he drew with his Tail, and his Angels was caſt out with him, and his Power Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mited, to have no more place in Heaven, neither in the Angels nor Stars, but if upon Earth he can draw them, which have an Angelical, Spiritual Gifts and bring them to degenerate from their gifts, in drawing one ſuch through that one, he gains many more, which looks at that one as an Example.</p>
            <p>Therefore every one to your Watch, and pray to be delivered from his Temptations, and come to Witneſs that Bleſſed Prayer, which is to ſay, Our Father which art in Heaven, hallowed be thy Name, thy Kingdom come, thy Will be done in Earth as it is Heaven, give us this Day our daily Bread, (that is every Day our Spiritual Bread, that we may know our Life, and accep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tance with and in thee, and out of Saans Power when he comes to Tempt, either in himſelf or through Inſtruments, ſo ſhall we in our Bodies, Witneſs a new Heaven, and a new Earth, a new Creation, wherein dwelleth Righteouſneſs) and to ſay forgive us our Treſpaſſes as we forgive them, that Treſpaſs againſt us, for if ye forgive Men their Treſpaſſes, your Heavenly Fathers will alſo forgive you, but if ye forgive not Men their Treſpaſſes, neither will your Father forgive your Treſpaſſes, (and the Exhortation is not to lay up for your ſelves, Treaſures upon Earth, where Moth and Ruſt doth Corrupt, and where Thieves break through, and Steal, but lay up for your ſelves Treaſures in Heaven, where neither Mo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>h
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:45364:5" rendition="simple:additions"/> nor Ruſt doth Corrupt, and where Thieves do not break through, not Steal) and them which Witneſs a growth in the Prayer, which our Lord Chriſt teached his Diſciples to pray, they deſire the Kingdom of God to come in Power and Glory, and his Will to be done in their Earth, as in Heaven, and to be delivered from the Evil of Temptation, and to know their Bread to come down from Heaven Day by Day, to feed their Souls, and to live in Obedience to the Goſpel, that his Power may take place, and that God may be Glorified in every Power upon Earth, to the Peace of their Salvation, yeilding Obedience to the Lamb of Peace, for God will be Glori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fied either in Mercy or Judgment, and if the World will not admit of a growth in the Chriſtian Faith, then how ſhall the Kingdoms of this World, become the Kingdoms of our Lord, and his Chriſt, which gives Peace, and Man is to be a new Heaven, and a new Earth, wherein dwelleth Righteouſneſs, 2 <hi>c,</hi> 3. and 13 <hi>v. Iſ.</hi> 65.17. <hi>v.</hi> 66 <hi>c.</hi> 21. <hi>v.</hi> and <hi>Revelations</hi> 21 <hi>c.</hi> 1 <hi>v.</hi> and ſuch a Heaven, and ſuch a Earth, will be far from Oppreſſion, but till the Dragon is caſt out of Mans Earth, as he was caſt down from Hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven, and Man to know a Second Birth to be Born again, and Created a new, in the Spirit of Truth tell this Spirit governs in Man, and in every Power, they will deſtroy in the Lion like Nature, and the Bear and Wolfs Nature, and God will be clear of the Gentiles, in manifeſting the Myſte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries of the Revelations, of the Goſpel of Peace, to them, and the Deſtructive Sword (not of the Goſpel) and its Power and Throne, ſeen from the Lamb of Peace, and his Power and Throne, the Lamb ſtood on the Mount <hi>Sion,</hi> and with him the Hundred and Forty and Four Thouſand, <hi>Ch.</hi> 14.1. <hi>v.</hi> which were redeemed from the Earth, and the great multitude, which no Man could Number of all Nations, and Kindreds, and People and Tongues, ſtood before the Throne, and before the Lamb, <hi>Rev.</hi> 7 <hi>c.</hi> 9 <hi>v.</hi> when the Dragon and Beaſt, and their Worſhippers were to be Tormented, and to have no reſt Day nor Night, and as afore-mentioned, the Lord will be clear of his Word, ſent to the Gentiles, and will call the Jews into the Goſpel of Peace, and will Spirit them, in his Work of Peace, among the Nations, and in the Revelations, there is a Revolution ſhewed by the Dragon, and Beaſt, the falſe Prophet, the falſe Spirit, and Church to come upon the Diſobedient Gent<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>les, as there came a Revolution upon the Diſobedient Jews, for their Rebellions, but a Remnant, which ſee the Evil of their Diſobedience, in the General were afflicted, and Mourned, and theſe believed and roſe w th Chriſt, in the Spring of the Goſpel notwithſtanding they were caſt out by their Bre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thren, but as ſaith the Apoſtle, whether ſhall we Obey, God or Man, Judge ye, and in this, they were to Judge the Laws of Heaven, is to be O<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>beyed, before the Laws of Men, and the Laws of Men with all Humility, which ſtand in the Chriſtian Liberty of the Goſpel of Peace, and to War againſt him, that is Faithful and True. is to Diſobey the Laws of Heaven, when the Proclamation is gone forth, for Peace on Earth, Good Will towards Men, and the Heavenly Hoſt Witneſſes, of the Proclamation for Peace, and of which Proclamation for Peace, Praiſe and Glory to God, the Shepherds gives the Account in Peace, <hi>Lu.</hi> 2 <hi>c.</hi> 14.15 <hi>v.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>And that Peace may be Proclaimed throughout the World, is the Prayer of one which is the leaſt in the Family of Heaven, and deſires to do the Will of God, and not my own Will.</hi>
            </p>
            <closer>
               <signed>Elizabeth Redford.</signed>
            </closer>
            <pb facs="tcp:45364:5"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
